Elspeth Ready

EMAIL: elspethready@gmail.com Website: https://elspethr.github.io/

CITIZENSHIP: Canadian with German permanent residency

Languages: **English** (First language); **French** (Professional proficiency); **German** (Intermediate, self-assessment CERF B2)

Summary

Interdisciplinary social scientist combining strong data science/quant skills with extensive experience collaborating with Indigenous communities and organizations. My primary areas of expertise include human dimensions of climate change and food security. Some examples of my work include validating food security assessment tools, calculating carbon emissions avoided through Inuit food production, and exploring Inuit concepts of stress (Inuktitut summary).

EDUCATION

2010 – 2016	Ph.D., Anthropology	Stanford University (USA)
2008 – 2010	M.A., Anthropology	Trent University (Canada)
2004-2008	B.A. Honors, Anthropology	University of Alberta (Canada)

Positions held

2019-present Senior Researcher, Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology, Department of

Human Behavior, Ecology and Culture

2017-present Courtesy Assistant Professor, Department of Anthropology, University of Florida

2017–2019 Postdoctoral Research Associate, Department of Sociology, University of Nebraska-Lincoln

2016–2017 Postdoctoral Scholar, Department of Anthropology, Stanford University

Consulting experience

2024 Consultant for Makivvik Corporation (a non-profit representing Nunavik Inuit): conducting commu-

nity consultations and providing logistical and organizational support to the scientific team

conducting environmental research for a protected-area project in Nunavik, Canada

2024 Cost-benefit analysis of the impacts of carbon tax in the Inuvialuit Settlement Region (Canada)

for the Inuvialuit Regional Corporation (which represents beneficiaries of the Inuvialuit land claim)

2024, 2022 Consultant for Makivvik Corporation: planned and facilitated elders' focus groups to document

Indigenous knowledge and to assess support for a planned conservation project in the Urqu region

(Kangiqsujuaq, Nunavik, Canada)

2021 Completed a report for the Inuvialuit Regional Corporation quantifying the traditional economy of the

Inuvialuit Region.

Since 2009 Copyediting work for English-second language writers, including several academic articles (example)

and a book manuscript.

SKILLS

>10 years of research on Indigenous food systems I have been conducting research on food security, with a focus on the Canadian Arctic, since 2013, including all phases of the work from survey instrument design through to analysis. I have also collaborated on projects focused on subsistence production among Martu in Australia, ethnic minorities in China, and rural villagers in Pemba, Tanzania. Over 30 peer-reviewed publications, including papers in top-ranked journals.

Outstanding written and oral communicator A recent report was described as "exceptionally well-crafted, and we thoroughly enjoyed reading it [...] the organization of the recommendations is commendable." My experience with Inuit communities has honed my skills in presenting the essential elements of research methods and findings to non-scientific audiences.

Extensive field research experience

Over 26 months of field experience in Indigenous communities, including Kangiqsujuaq and Ulukhaktok (Canada) and Parnngurr (Australia). Deep knowledge of **quantitative and qualitative social science methods**, including questionnaire design and assessment, structured, semi-structured and open-ended interviewing techniques. I have experience consulting with community leaders about research design and data management plans, and obtaining informed consent in the context of research.

Advanced data analysis skills

Highly proficient in **R** for a wide range of **statistical methods** including Bayesian and frequentist statistics (including economic modelling), item-response theory and social network analysis. Working knowledge of **Python**, **databases**, and **source control** systems. R code for all papers since 2018 is available on github.

Strong project management and leadership skills I established my research program in Kangiqsujuaq in 2010 and since then have led all aspects of the project, including community consultations, writing grant applications, budgeting, field logistics, data collection, data analysis, training and leading local teams of research assistants, and advising and mentoring graduate students and postdocs.